Right before the Chuseok holidays…
추석 직전 연휴…
I'm sorry I was late. There was heavy traffic.
늦어서 미안해요. 교통량이 많았습니다.
No, it's fine. I just came out too.
아니요, 괜찮아요. 저도 방금 나왔어요.
Hey, my cousin got married pretty late.
안녕하세요, 제 사촌이 꽤 늦게 결혼했어요.
So everyone at the wedding cried.
그래서 결혼식에 참석한 모든 사람들이 울었습니다.
And my mom packed me food from the buffet.
그리고 엄마는 뷔페에서 음식을 포장해 주셨어요.
Look at all this food.
이 음식을 보세요.
Goodness.
선량.
This sure makes us feel like normal people, doesn't it?
이것은 확실히 우리를 평범한 사람들처럼 느끼게 만듭니다 . 그렇죠?
I went to a wedding on a Saturday.
토요일에 결혼식에 갔어요.
And we're stuck downtown in the middle of a congested road.
그리고 우리는 혼잡한 도로 한가운데에 갇혀있습니다.
It'd be perfect if only we weren't headed to visit someone in prison.
우리가 감옥에 있는 누군가를 만나러 가지만 않는다면 완벽할 것입니다 .
Seoul Tollgate announced that cars leaving Seoul…
서울톨게이트, 서울 출발 차량 발표…
Hey. How do office workers wear ties every day?
여기요. 직장인들은 넥타이를 매일 어떻게 매나요?
This is so suffocating.
너무 숨막히네요.
And the Honam Expressway…
그리고 호남고속도로…
Gosh. I should've brought some clothes to change into.
이런. 갈아입을 옷을 좀 가져왔어야 했는데 .
Do you want to switch shoes at least?
적어도 신발을 바꾸고 싶습니까?
No, it's okay.
아니 괜찮아.
-Do you want rice cakes? -Sorry?
-떡볶이 먹을래? -죄송합니다?
-Open your mouth. -I'm good.
-입을 열. -난 괜찮아.
Open up.
열어라.
There. Chew it.
거기. 씹어보세요.
That's it.
그게 다야.
Let's go.
갑시다.
SEOUL DETENTION CENTER
서울구치소
Isn't it nice?
멋지지 않나요?
It does look big and nice.
크고 멋져보이네요.
I spent two months' salary on this. It better be nice.
나는 이것에 두 달치 월급을 썼다. 좋을 것 같아요.
You're spending more than you're earning.
당신은 버는 것보다 더 많은 돈을 쓰고 있습니다.
You need the right tools to put your skills to use.
기술을 활용하려면 올바른 도구가 필요합니다 .
Hey, this kind of looks lame.
아, 이거 좀 허접해 보이는데.
I'll put it away.
치워두겠습니다.
I'm comfortable with it. Let me use it.
나는 그것이 편안하다. 사용하겠습니다.
-You want to? -Yes.
-하고 싶나요? -예.
-Okay, it's all yours. -Okay.
-좋아, 다 네 거야. -좋아요.
All right. Hold on.
괜찮은. 기다리다.
This should be…
이것은…
Should we put this here?
이것을 여기에 넣어야 할까요?
KEEP QUIET
조용히 하세요
Inmate 4709, you have visitors.
수감자 4709, 방문객이 왔습니다.
Who's here?
여기 누구야?
Look at him dusting off his feet again. Gosh.
그가 다시 발의 먼지를 털고 있는 것을 보십시오 . 이런.
-That fool. -Just go, will you?
- 그 바보. - 그냥 가, 응?
-Jeez. -Seriously.
- 이런. -진지하게.
Hurry up. The officer is waiting.
서둘러요. 경찰관이 기다리고 있습니다.
-Goodness. -Come on.
-선량. -어서 해봐요.
Darn you.
젠장.
-I'm sorry, man. -What the…
-미안해요. -뭐야…
You can't blindside me like this.
이렇게 나를 눈이 멀게 할 수는 없습니다.
I can't even stand the way he walks.
나는 그가 걷는 방식조차 참을 수 없습니다.
All right.
괜찮은.
We're not here to interrogate you, so relax.
우리는 당신을 심문하러 온 것이 아니니 안심하세요.
Did you dress up to see me?
나를 만나려고 옷을 차려입었나요?
Why do you ask?
왜 물어보나요?
I feel special.
나는 특별하다고 느낀다.
Isn't it all over now?
이제 다 끝난 것 아닌가?
Do you think it's over?
끝났다고 생각하시나요?
You caught me.
너는 나를 잡았다.
Mr. Cho, we still have many questions for you.
조 선생님, 아직 질문이 많이 남아있습니다.
But I told you everything last time.
그런데 지난번에 다 말했어요.
I told that lady everything too.
나도 그 여자한테 다 말했어.
She is a detective, not a "lady."
그녀는 '아가씨'가 아니라 탐정이다.
We want to hear more about you,
우리는 당신에 대해 더 듣고 싶습니다.
not about the case.
사건에 관한 것이 아닙니다.
You could tell us about your childhood
당신의 어린 시절에 대해 말해 줄 수 있습니다
or about what you usually feel.
또는 평소에 느끼는 것에 대해.
It's just for our record, so don't worry about it.
저희의 기록을 위한 것이므로 걱정하지 않으셔도 됩니다.
Right.
오른쪽.
Well…
잘…
Is there anything you'd like to tell us?
우리에게 하고 싶은 말이 있나요?
It's okay. You can tell us anything.
괜찮아요. 당신은 우리에게 무엇이든 말할 수 있습니다.
You're not interrogating me,
당신은 나를 심문하는 것이 아닙니다.
but you want to hear my story?
그런데 내 이야기 ​​듣고 싶어?
Yes.
예.
No one wants to hear my story.
아무도 내 이야기를 듣고 싶어하지 않습니다.
-Why do you? -We visited your place.
-왜 당신을? -우리는 당신의 집을 방문했습니다.
My place?
내 집?
Yes, it was very clean.
네, 아주 깨끗했어요.
Everything was neatly organized,
모든 것이 깔끔하게 정리되어 있었고,
even your socks.
양말까지도요.
I don't like it when things are messy.
나는 일이 지저분한 것을 좋아하지 않습니다.
I know.
알아요.
So you must be having a hard time here.
그러니까 여기서 힘든 시간을 보내고 있을 거에요.
Right?
오른쪽?
Every day, strangers who committed heinous crimes
매일매일 극악무도한 범죄를 저지르는 낯선 사람들
are eating and sleeping with you.
너랑 같이 먹고 자고 있어.
It must be awful.
정말 끔찍할 것 같아요.
It is awful.
정말 끔찍해요.
So…
그래서…
why don't you tell us more about yourself?
당신에 대해 좀 더 이야기해 보는 게 어때요?
The people here will try to treat you as one of them.
여기 사람들은 당신을 그들 중 하나로 대하려고 노력할 것입니다.
But in our eyes,
그러나 우리 눈에는
you seem a little different.
당신은 좀 다른 것 같아요.
Well…
잘…
They don't even wash often.
그들은 자주 씻지도 않습니다.
They stink, and the cell is small and filthy.
악취가 나고 감방은 작고 불결합니다.
It's really driving me crazy.
정말 미치게 만드네요.
Right, I'm sure.
그렇죠, 확실해요.
So this was what we thought.
그래서 이것이 우리가 생각한 것입니다.
Perhaps you…
아마도 너…
didn't actually intend to kill Soo-hyun--
사실 수현을 죽일 생각은 없었는데..
That's right, I…
그렇죠, 저는…
I never intended to kill her.
나는 결코 그녀를 죽일 생각이 없었습니다.
That's why we want to hear your story.
그래서 우리는 당신의 이야기를 듣고 싶습니다.
To understand why you're different from the others.
왜 당신 이 다른 사람들과 다른지 이해하기 위해서입니다.
Looks like you've lost some weight.
살이 좀 빠진 것 같네요.
Have you been eating well?
식사는 잘 하셨나요?
Then why don't we
그럼 우리는 어때?
eat something first before we start talking?
얘기하기 전에 뭐라도 먼저 먹어볼까 ?
How are you feeling?
기분이 어때요?
I got to have a proper meal for a change.
기분 전환을 위해 제대로 된 식사를 해야 해요.
I wish every day was like today.
매일이 오늘 같았으면 좋겠어요.
Do you regret it?
후회하시나요?
She shouldn't have been there.
그녀는 거기에 있어서는 안 됐어요.
What do you mean by she shouldn't have been there?
그녀가 거기에 있어서는 안 됐다는 게 무슨 뜻이에요 ?
Blame the girl's bad luck.
그 소녀의 불운을 비난하십시오.
It's Soo-hyun.
수현이에요.
Her name.
그녀의 이름.
Lee Soo-hyun.
이수현.
Had she not come to that place that day,
그 날 그 사람이 그 곳에 오지 않았더라면,
nothing would have happened to her or me.
그녀나 나에게는 아무 일도 일어나지 않았을 것이다.
Do you think…
당신은 생각합니까?
this incident is her fault?
이 사건이 그 사람 잘못인가요?
I'm saying it's her fault for catching my attention.
내 관심을 끈 것은 그녀의 잘못이라는 뜻이다 .
I wonder what was on his mind
그 사람은 무슨 생각을 했을지 궁금하네요
as Cho Hyun-gil was watching such an innocent child.
이렇게 순진한 아이를 조현길이 지켜보고 있던 것처럼 .
Why is he different from us?
그 사람은 왜 우리와 다른가요?
Are you from Samcheonpo?
삼천포 출신이신가요?
I don't hear a dialect though.
하지만 방언은 들리지 않습니다.
I moved to Seoul when I was 15.
나는 15살 때 서울로 이사했다.
In eighth grade?
8학년 때요?
I didn't go to middle school.
나는 중학교에 가지 않았다.
I started working after elementary school.
초등학교 졸업 후 일을 시작했어요.
What kind of work?
어떤 종류의 일?
I worked at factories,
공장에서 일했는데,
sold fish, and worked at butcher shops.
생선을 팔고 정육점에서 일했다.
I did everything I was told to do.
나는 내가 하라는 말을 다 했다.
I also had many jobs.
나 역시 많은 직업을 갖고 있었다.
My family was very poor when I was young.
제가 어렸을 때 우리 가족은 매우 가난했습니다.
Since I'm the eldest son,
제가 큰 아들이니까.
I had to help my parents on their farm and sell our harvest.
나는 부모님의 농장 일을 돕고 수확물을 팔아야 했습니다.
I did all sorts of things.
나는 온갖 일을했습니다.
Detective, what was your name again?
형사님, 이름이 뭐였나요?
My name?
내 이름?
I'm Kook Young-soo.
저는 국영수입니다.
Detective Kook, then did you also quit school after elementary school?
국형사님, 그럼 당신도 초등학교 졸업하고 학교를 그만뒀나요?
I entered middle school a year later than everyone else.
나는 남들보다 1년 늦게 중학교에 입학했다 .
I see. At least you went to middle school.
알겠어요. 적어도 중학교는 다녔잖아.
You think you two are different?
너희 둘이 다른 것 같아?
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
You were both poor, and both of you struggled.
당신은 둘 다 가난했고 둘 다 어려움을 겪었습니다.
But he attended middle school, so it's different.
하지만 중학교를 다녔기 때문에 얘기가 다릅니다.
I could've been different too.
나도 다를 수 있었어.
You think that's why you became a criminal?
그것 때문에 범죄자가 되었다고 생각하시나요?
Because you're a dropout?
당신이 중퇴자라서?
Well…
잘…
I…
나…
-Detective. -Yes.
-형사. -예.
Can you get me a soda?
탄산음료 좀 갖다 주시겠어요?
I have a habit of drinking one
한 잔씩 마시는 습관이 있어요
after every meal.
매 식사 후에.
She shouldn't have been there.
그녀는 거기에 있어서는 안 됐어요.
Blame the girl's bad luck.
소녀의 불운을 비난합니다.
Hey.
여기요.
-Are you all right? -Of course.
-괜찮으세요? -물론.
Let's go.
갑시다.
You quit smoking.
담배를 끊으셨어요.
Yes, what's up?
응, 무슨 일이야?
Why do you carry a lighter around?
라이터는 왜 들고 다니나요?
Oh, this thing?
아, 이거요?
For emergencies.
비상용.
I'm sure there will come a day when I'll crave a smoke.
언젠가 담배가 땡길 날이 올 거라 믿습니다 .
If I don't have a lighter at that time,
그때 라이터가 없었다면,
I may seriously go crazy.
정말 미칠 수도 있어요.
PROPOSAL
제안
We just got started,
이제 막 시작했어요.
so let us do this for just one more year.
그럼 1년만 더 해보자.
Go ahead.
계속하세요.
We won't cause any trouble.
우리는 어떤 문제도 일으키지 않을 것입니다.
Right here. Please.
바로 여기에. 제발.
So please… Help me out.
그러니 제발... 도와주세요.
Sit down.
앉아.
-Goodness. -Just one more year.
-선량. -1년만 더.
This year's college entrance exam must have been easy.
올해 대학입시는 쉬웠을 것 같아요.
-Arms down. -The cut-off scores.
-팔을 내리세요. -컷오프 점수.
They went up by as much as ten points.
10포인트나 올랐습니다.
-Reported by Lee Yong-nam. -Done.
-이용남 기자가 제보합니다. - 완료.
The college exam score cut-off
대학 시험 점수 컷오프
for SNU's Humanities Department…
서울대학교 인문학부…
-Salute! -We'll do our best!
-경례! - 최선을 다하겠습니다!
JANUARY 2001
2001년 1월
MARCH 2001
2001년 3월
MAY 2001
2001년 5월
A terrorist attack on the US put Americans and people around the world
미국에 대한 테러 공격으로 미국인 과 전 세계 사람들이 혼란에 빠졌습니다.
in great shock.
큰 충격을 받았습니다.
SEPTEMBER 2001
2001년 9월
One second.
1초.
OCTOBER 2001
2001년 10월
NOVEMBER 2001
2001년 11월
DECEMBER 2001
2001년 12월
-Excuse me. -One second.
-실례합니다. -일초.
DECEMBER 2001
2001년 12월
JANUARY 2002
2002년 1월
-Yes. -If you give us one more chance,
-네. - 한번만 더 기회를 주시면
we'll repay with good results.
좋은 결과로 보답하겠습니다.
Yes, sir.
알겠습니다.
EXTENDED BY ONE YEAR
1년 연장
-Thank you!
-감사합니다!
-Go, Korea! Hey! -Go, Korea!
-가자, 한국! 여기요! -가자, 한국!
All right!
알았어!
NOVEMBER 2002
2002년 11월
Good grief!
안타깝습니다!
Hey, let him go. Officer!
이봐, 그를 놔줘. 장교!
You can take him away.
그를 데려가시면 됩니다.
Darn it.
젠장.
DECEMBER 2002
2002년 12월
I'm aware.
알겠습니다.
So why did you go that far and commit that crime?
그렇다면 왜 그렇게 멀리까지 가서 그런 범죄를 저질렀나요?
My gosh, these detectives.
맙소사, 이 형사들
NEW HOPE!
새로운 희망!
Although the temperature is below zero,
기온은 영하이지만
the beach is filled with people waiting for the first sunrise.
해변은 첫 일출을 기다리는 사람들로 가득 차 있습니다.
I got some steamed buns.
찐빵을 좀 받았어요.
The number of people…
인원수…
FEBRUARY 2003
2003년 2월
MARCH 2003
2003년 3월
APRIL 2003
2003년 4월
JULY 2003
2003년 7월
AUGUST 2003
2003년 8월
It's been so long since our last team dinner.
우리 팀의 마지막 저녁 식사 이후로 너무 오랜 시간이 흘렀습니다 .
Eat up while you can. A day like this may never come again.
먹을 수 있을 때 먹어라. 이런 날이 다시는 오지 않을 수도 있습니다.
Eat up. I'll do it.
먹어라. 나는 그것을 할 거 야.
It's fine. I'm an expert at grilling, so I never let anyone else do it.
괜찮아. 나는 굽는 일에 전문가이기 때문에 절대 남에게 시켜서는 안 된다.
-Let me show you my skills. Give it to me. -No, sir.
-내 실력을 보여주지. 그걸 나에게주세요. -아닙니다.
Just eat this. It's hot.
이것만 먹어라. 그것은 뜨겁다.
It's good.
좋다.
Please evaluate my skills.
내 실력을 평가해 주세요.
-I'll eat it myself. -My gosh.
- 내가 직접 먹을게. -이럴수가.
-You should eat too. -Okay.
-너도 먹어야 해. -좋아요.
All right.
괜찮은.
Let's continue to do well.
계속해서 잘 지내보자.
Okay.
좋아요.
-Great work. -Bottoms up.
-훌륭한 일. -원샷이야.
Weather newsflash.
날씨 속보.
The typhoon is heading north,
태풍이 북쪽으로 향하고 있습니다.
making many parents worry as they wait for their children.
많은 부모들이 자녀를 기다리면서 걱정하게 만듭니다.
Typhoon 14, also known as Maemi,
14호 태풍, 매미
will cause strong winds to blow
강풍이 불겠습니다
along with heavy rain throughout the entire country.
전국에 폭우가 내리고 있습니다 .
The wind speed of Maemi
매미의 풍속
can reach up to 60m per second.
초당 최대 60m까지 도달할 수 있습니다.
It first headed to Taiwan, then suddenly changed course
처음에는 대만으로 향했다가 갑자기 방향을 바꾸었습니다
toward the Korean Peninsula.
한반도를 향해
Honey, I'm home.
자기야 나 왔어.
What…
무엇…
No…
아니요…
Honey!
꿀!
What's…
무엇입니까…
-There's another one. -No, wait…
- 또 하나 있어요. -아니, 잠깐만…
I WAS SO ANGRY
나는 너무 화가 났어요
BECAUSE SHE DIED BEFORE I COULD DO ANYTHING
내가 아무것도 하기 전에 그녀가 죽었으니까요
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
서울지방경찰청
So do you know who the new chief is?
그럼 새 추장이 누구인지 아시나요?
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
Right.
오른쪽.
What's wrong? What's with that face?
뭐가 문제 야? 그 얼굴은 뭐죠?
Oh, you're here.
아, 여기 계시군요.
Hey, good morning, Tae-gu.
안녕, 태구야.
Have you been well?
잘 지내셨나요?
Why didn't you tell me?
왜 나에게 말하지 않았나요?
You could've at least given me a heads-up.
최소한 나에게 미리 알림을 줬을 수도 있었을 텐데.
Everyone already knew.
다들 이미 알고 있었어요.
I didn't need to do that.
나는 그렇게 할 필요가 없었습니다.
Except for me, who has to take orders from him.
그 사람의 명령을 받아야 하는 나만 빼고요 .
I mean, I thought…
내 말은, 내 생각엔…
you already knew too.
당신도 이미 알고 있었죠.
Okay.
좋아요.
-Goodness, hello. -Sir.
-맙소사, 안녕하세요. -선생님.
I'm Kim Bong-sik, the new chief of the Special Crime Squad.
신임 특수수사대 반장 김봉식 입니다 .
-Hello. -Nice to meet you.
-안녕하세요. -만나서 반가워요.
I hope we all get along.
우리 모두 잘 지내길 바랍니다.
-Yes. -It's nice to meet you.
-예. -그것은 당신을 만나서 반가워요.
Let's grab some soju.
소주 한잔 하자.
-Sure. -Okay.
-확신하는. -좋아요.
If you knew Kim Bong-sik was coming as our new chief,
김봉식이 새 팀장으로 온다는 걸 알았더라면,
you of all people could've let me know.
당신이라면 나에게 알려줄 수도 있었을 텐데.
I thought it would only bother you if I told you ahead of time.
미리 말하면 방해만 될 거라 생각했어요 .
Also, nothing would change anyway.
또한 어차피 아무것도 변하지 않을 것입니다.
Nothing could be changed,
아무것도 바뀔 수 없었고,
so I should be kept in the dark?
그럼 나는 어둠 속에 갇혀 있어야 하는 걸까?
No, that's not what I meant.
아니, 내 말은 그런 뜻이 아니었어.
Well…
잘…
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
There's no need for you to apologize.
사과하실 필요는 없습니다.
Forget it.
잊어 버려.
It probably wasn't easy for you either.
아마 당신에게도 쉽지 않았을 겁니다.
Does the Analysis Team know?
분석팀은 알고 있나요?
The Analysis Team?
분석팀?
Back when they were at Jungbu Station,
예전에 중부역에 있었을 때,
I heard Song Ha-young once screwed over Chief Kim Bong-sik.
송하영이 김봉식 과장을 망쳤다는 얘기를 들은 적이 있다.
People in this field really love rumors,
이 분야 사람들은 소문을 참 좋아하는데,
don't they?
그렇지 않나요?
RAPE AND MUTILATION MURDERER HWANG DAE-SUN
강간 및 훼손 살인자 황대선
Why are you back?
왜 돌아왔나요?
We still do not understand
우리는 아직도 이해하지 못한다
why you committed these crimes, Mr. Hwang.
황씨, 왜 이런 범죄를 저질렀나요?
So we came to hear the story of your life, Mr. Hwang.
그래서 황 선생님의 인생 이야기를 듣고자 왔습니다 .
What story?
무슨 이야기요?
Well, can you share stories of your childhood?
그럼, 당신 의 어린 시절 이야기를 들려주실 수 있나요?
Why do you want to hear my sad childhood story?
내 슬픈 어린 시절 이야기를 왜 듣고 싶니 ?
I guess you have lots of bad memories.
안 좋은 기억이 많으실 것 같아요.
In that case,
그 경우,
can you tell me one thing that made you the angriest?
당신을 가장 화나게 만든 한 가지를 말해줄 수 있나요 ?
It's my dad.
우리 아빠예요.
He always beat me up without a reason.
그는 늘 이유 없이 나를 때렸다.
He'd beat me up during meals, and beat me for going to school.
그는 식사 중에 나를 때렸고, 학교에 간다는 이유로 나를 때렸습니다.
I sometimes took a few days off
가끔 며칠 쉬기도 했고
because he hurt me so badly.
그 사람이 나에게 너무 큰 상처를 주었기 때문이다.
I was also stripped down to my underwear
나도 속옷까지 다 벗겼어
and got kicked out of the house.
그리고 집에서 쫓겨났습니다.
I stood by the front gate.
나는 정문 앞에 섰다.
So if your neighborhood friends saw you,
그러니 동네 친구들이 당신을 본다면,
they would've teased you a lot.
그 사람들이 당신을 많이 놀렸을 겁니다.
Kids made fun of me
아이들이 나를 놀렸어요
until I went to middle school.
중학교에 들어갈 때까지.
I'd beat them up too.
나도 그들을 때릴 것입니다.
I never hung out with them.
나는 그들과 어울리지 않았습니다.
Those emotions must have been tough on you.
그 감정이 당신에게 힘들었을 것입니다.
It's humiliating to be stripped.
벗겨지는 것은 굴욕적이다.
How did you usually deal with your anger?
평소에 분노를 어떻게 처리하셨나요?
There wasn't much I could do as a kid.
어렸을 때 할 수 있는 일이 별로 없었어요.
All I could do was kill animals.
내가 할 수 있는 일은 동물을 죽이는 것뿐이었다.
I killed my neighbor's cow with a sickle.
나는 낫으로 이웃의 소를 죽였습니다.
I caught a dog in my neighborhood and watched it jump and bark
동네 개 한 마리를 잡아서 뛰고 짖는 모습을 지켜봤습니다.
in hot, boiling water.
뜨겁고 끓는 물에.
Watching that got me off.
그것을 보면서 나는 기분이 좋아졌다.
My dad stripped me and kicked me out so many times.
아버지는 나를 수없이 벗기고 쫓아냈습니다.
So I still hate it when my body is exposed.
그래서 아직도 몸이 노출되는 걸 싫어해요 .
It infuriates me.
그것은 나를 화나게 한다.
No matter how hot it is, I never wear shorts or short sleeves.
아무리 더워도 반바지나 반팔은 절대 입지 않아요.
After you killed animals,
동물을 죽인 후,
did you dismember them too?
너도 그 사람들을 해체했니?
Sometimes.
때때로.
I tried cutting them up.
나는 그들을 자르려고 노력했다.
I learned to cook at a restaurant.
나는 레스토랑에서 요리하는 법을 배웠다.
Using a knife to cut them into pieces was fun.
칼을 사용하여 조각으로 자르는 것이 재미있었습니다.
Your second female victim.
두 번째 여성 피해자입니다.
Is that why you cut off the flesh on her leg
그래서 다리 살을 잘라내는 건가요?
after you raped and murdered her?
당신이 그녀를 강간하고 살해한 후에요?
I don't know.
모르겠습니다.
I wanted to cut it off when she was alive.
살아있을 때 잘라내고 싶었어요.
But she kept moving, and her blood splattered.
하지만 그녀는 계속 움직이고 있었고, 피가 튀었습니다.
So I stopped for a bit.
그래서 잠시 멈췄습니다.
After I killed her,
내가 그녀를 죽인 후,
I sat next to her and tried to cut it off again.
나는 그녀 옆에 앉아서 다시 그것을 끊으려고 노력했다.
But I don't remember much because I was drunk.
그런데 술에 취해 기억이 잘 안 난다 .
Then you took it home.
그런 다음 집으로 가져갔습니다.
But no one saw you?
그런데 아무도 당신을 못 봤나요?
It was dripping in blood.
피가 뚝뚝 떨어지고 있었습니다.
I bet it must've scared people.
아마 사람들이 겁을 먹었을 거예요.
Why? They wouldn't know what it was.
왜? 그들은 그것이 무엇인지 몰랐을 것입니다.
I thought it was meat for a second
순간 고기인줄 알았어요
when I woke up the next day.
다음날 일어났을 때.
You don't remember?
기억하지 못하시나요?
Or do you not want to talk to us?
아니면 우리랑 얘기하고 싶지 않아?
It's both.
둘 다입니다.
Do I have to tell you everything?
내가 당신에게 모든 것을 말해야 합니까?
You said it wasn't an interrogation.
심문이 아니라고 하더군요.
GWANGJU PRISON
광주교도소
-Have a good day. -You too.
-좋은 하루 보내세요. -너도.
Hwang Dae-sun definitely shows the behaviors of serial killers.
황대선은 연쇄살인마의 면모를 확실히 보여준다.
Right. But why do you think he cut off the flesh on her leg?
오른쪽. 그런데 왜 그가 그녀의 다리 살을 잘라냈다고 생각하시나요 ?
It looks like he didn't know.
그는 몰랐던 것 같습니다.
I think his rage against his abusive father
내 생각엔 학대하는 아버지에 대한 그의 분노가
developed into abnormal sexual behaviors.
비정상적인 성적 행동으로 발전하게 됩니다.
Then his rage caused him to mutilate the body too.
그러자 그의 분노로 인해 몸도 절단되었습니다.
Right.
오른쪽.
Many organizations are trying to support flood victims
많은 조직이 홍수 피해자를 지원하기 위해 노력하고 있습니다
from Typhoon Maemi which struck the Korean Peninsula pretty hard.
한반도를 강타한 태풍 매미
The civil organizations…
시민단체…
How may I help you?
어떻게 도와드릴까요?
Is this the Behavioral Analysis Team?
행동분석팀인가요?
-Yes. -Where's Song Ha-young?
-예. -송하영은 어디 있지?
Inspector Song? He's out for an interview.
송 검사님? 그는 인터뷰를 하러 나갔다.
"Inspector"?
"조사관"?
Should I tell him you stopped by when he comes back?
그가 돌아오면 들렀다고 말해야 할까요 ?
SKY, WIND, STAR, AND POETRY BY YUN DONG-JU
하늘과 바람과 별과 시 윤동주
He hasn't changed.
그는 변하지 않았습니다.
What brings you here?
여기에서 당신을 제공합니다?
Don't mind me.
신경쓰지 마세요.
Get back to work.
다시 일하세요.
It's like nothing ever happened. This isn't fair.
아무 일도 일어나지 않은 것 같습니다. 이건 불공평해요.
Sorry?
죄송합니다?
The weather.
날씨.
The weather being this nice isn't fair.
이렇게 좋은 날씨는 불공평해요.
The pain and sense of loss.
고통과 상실감.
The suffering
고통
is only up to the victims to bear.
그건 피해자가 감당할 뿐입니다.
I bet some people are enjoying this good weather.
이 좋은 날씨를 즐기고 계시는 분들도 계시리라 믿습니다 .
All right.
괜찮은.
He's not even investigating the case.
그는 사건을 조사하지도 않습니다.
Why is he reading the case reports for the detectives?
그는 왜 형사들의 사건 보고서를 읽고 있는 걸까요 ?
Seriously. This nosy jerk.
진지하게. 이 참견쟁이.
Hey. I'll tell him when he comes--
여기요. 그가 오면 말할게요--
You punk!
이 멍청아!
"Hey"?
"여기요"?
Read what it says on my business card.
내 명함에 적힌 내용을 읽어보세요.
"Special Crime Squad Chief, Kim Bong-sik."
"특수수사대장 김봉식."
Are you blind?
당신은 장님입니까?
I'm sorry.
죄송합니다.
You seem to have picked up bad habits from Song Ha-young.
송하영에게서 나쁜 버릇을 물려받은 것 같다 .
You're still wet behind your ears.
귀 뒤는 아직 젖어 있어요.
This is the Behavioral Analysis Team's office.
행동분석팀 사무실 입니다 .
You need to tell me why you are here.
당신이 여기에 있는 이유를 나에게 말해야 합니다.
You are going to make me repeat myself.
당신은 내가 반복하게 만들 것입니다.
You just mind your own business!
당신은 당신 자신의 일에만 신경쓰세요!
I'm back.
나는 돌아왔다.
Assistant Inspector Song.
송 부검사.
I hear you're an inspector now.
지금은 검사관이라고 들었습니다.
Inspector Song.
송 검사님.
Goodness. You seem well.
선량. 당신은 괜찮아 보인다.
What do you guys do here?
너희들은 여기서 무엇을 합니까?
Why are you dressed up?
왜 옷을 입고 있어요?
Why are you here?
당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
I don't expect you to give me a warm welcome.
나는 당신이 나를 따뜻하게 환영해 줄 것이라고 기대하지 않습니다 .
But it's only polite to say hello when you see someone.
하지만 누군가를 만났을 때 인사하는 것은 예의일 뿐입니다 .
Don't you agree?
동의하지 않나요?
Seriously. This team is full of rude punks.
진지하게. 이 팀은 무례한 놈들로 가득 차 있습니다.
I'm Statistics Analyst Jung Woo-ju.
통계분석원 정우주 입니다.
Statistics analyst?
통계 분석가?
You guys have difficult titles here.
여기 어려운 제목이 있습니다.
Dumb people won't be able to remember them.
멍청한 사람들 은 기억 하지 못할 것이다 .
What was it called?
이름이 무엇이었나요?
Right. A profiler.
오른쪽. 프로파일러.
If you're here to talk to me,
나랑 얘기하러 오셨다면,
let's talk outside.
밖에서 얘기하자.
I have nothing to say to you in private.
나는 당신에게 개인적으로 할 말이 없습니다.
I just wanted to come to say hello.
그냥 인사하러 오고 싶었어요.
And I wanted to check out what you do here.
그리고 나는 당신이 여기서 무엇을 하는지 확인하고 싶었습니다 .
Why is the door open? Did…
문은 왜 열려있나요? 했다…
It's been a while, Captain Kook.
오랜만이에요, 국 선장님.
I was transferred to the Special Crime Squad.
저는 특수수사대 에 배치되었습니다 .
We'll be seeing each other often. I look forward to working with you.
우리 자주 만나요. 난 너랑 같이 일하기를 기대하고있다.
-Okay. -It was nice to see everyone.
-좋아요. -다들 만나서 반가웠어요.
Right. I bought this for you.
오른쪽. 나는 당신을 위해 이것을 샀습니다.
I almost forgot.
나는 거의 잊었다.
You still eat chocolates
아직도 초콜릿을 먹나요?
like a little kid, right?
어린아이 같죠?
Even if we don't want to, you'll see me every day.
우리가 원하지 않더라도 당신은 나를 매일 보게 될 것입니다.
Let's put our past behind us.
우리의 과거는 뒤로 미뤄두자.
See you around.
주위에 당신을보고.
Who was that?
그게 누구 였나?
Just as I heard, he's one rude cop.
내가 들은 대로 그 사람은 무례한 경찰이에요.
I was wondering how great his career was going
그의 경력이 얼마나 좋을지 궁금했습니다.
after he stabbed me, his mentor, in the back.
그 사람 이 자신의 멘토인 내 등을 찔렀을 때요 .
You've got to be kidding me. An inspector?
지금 농담하고 계시군요. 검사관?
NOVEMBER 1996
1996년 11월
Search every nook and cranny of the neighborhood.
이웃의 구석구석을 검색하세요 .
He's wearing a black jacket with a hoodie and black sneakers.
그는 검은색 재킷 과 후드티, 검은색 운동화를 입고 있습니다.
Find him now!
지금 그를 찾아보세요!
I'm chasing a suspicious man who fits the description.
설명에 딱 맞는 수상한 남자를 쫓고 있어요 .
I'm sorry. I lost him.
죄송합니다. 나는 그를 잃었습니다.
Yoon Tae-gu, where are you?
윤태구, 어디 있나요?
Where are you?
당신은 어디에 있나요?
Let go of me, you bastard.
날 놔, 이 새끼야.
Darn it.
젠장.
Jung Soo-chan.
정수찬.
You're under arrest
너를 체포한다
for robbery, murder, and fleeing.
강도, 살인, 도망을 위해.
You have the right to consult an attorney.
귀하는 변호사와 상담할 권리가 있습니다.
-And to remain silent. -Get him!
-그리고 침묵을 지키세요. - 잡아요!
Did you catch him?
그를 잡았나요?
Gosh. You really are a detective now.
이런. 이제 당신은 정말 탐정이군요.
Hey. We got him.
여기요. 우리는 그를 잡았습니다.
Don't stand there. Get him.
거기 서 있지 마세요. 그를 잡아라.
Yoon Tae-gu caught Jung Soo-chan.
윤태구가 정수찬을 붙잡았다.
Nice, Detective Yoon.
반가워요, 윤형사님.
She got him.
그녀는 그를 잡았습니다.
This punk.
이 펑크.
You set an example
당신은 모범을 보였습니다
for your fellow officers by promptly arresting
즉시 체포하여 동료 경찰관을 위해
a robbery and murder suspect
강도 및 살인 용의자
who was on the run after committing a brutal crime.
잔혹한 범죄를 저지른 뒤 도주 중이던 사람 .
Hence, I hereby award Inspector Yoon Tae-gu.
이에 윤태구 경감에게 표창장을 드립니다.
JUNGBU POLICE STATION SPECIAL PROMOTION CEREMONY
중부경찰서 특별승진식
Yoon Tae-gu!
윤태구!
-You're amazing. -Tae-gu, you rock.
-너 굉장하다. -대구야, 너 굉장해.
-Well done! -Go, Yoon Tae-gu!
-잘하셨어요! -가자, 윤태구!
Oh, my. You really look like a cop now.
어머. 이제 정말 경찰처럼 보이시네요.
I thought she wouldn't last and get married.
나는 그녀가 지속되지 못하고 결혼할 것이라고 생각했습니다.
-Gosh. She looks great. -You'll be the commissioner in no time.
-맙소사. 그녀는 멋져 보인다. -당신은 곧 위원이 될 것입니다.
-Tae-gu can definitely do that. -Of course.
-대구는 분명 그럴 수 있어요. -물론.
Could you take a photo of us?
우리 사진 좀 찍어 주시겠어요?
-Sure. -Can we join?
-확신하는. - 우리 같이 할 수 있을까?
You got a special promotion thanks to Ha-young.
하영이 덕분에 특별 승진을 하게 됐어요 .
I'm surprised you're holding out well, Tae-gu.
태구야, 잘 버티고 있어서 놀랐다 .
Okay, let's try that one more time.
좋아요, 한 번 더 시도해 보겠습니다.
Nice. All right, smile.
멋진. 알았어, 웃어봐.
Okay.
좋아요.
Captain.
선장.
-Captain Yoon. -Yes?
-윤 선장. -예?
Superintendent Baek wants to see you.
백 총감님이 뵙고 싶어 하십니다.
Superintendent Baek? Why?
백 총감? 왜?
I have no idea.
나는 모른다.
He asked for Chief Kim Bong-sik too, but I don't know where he is.
김봉식 과장도 데려오라고 했는데 어디 있는지 모르겠어요.
Cheers.
건배.
It's nice to have you back.
다시 뵙게 되어 반갑습니다.
Seeing you're the only one welcoming me,
나를 반겨주는 사람은 너뿐인 걸 보니
I'm not sure whether I've been doing well so far.
지금까지 잘 지내왔는지 모르겠습니다 .
Come on.
어서 해봐요.
I really meant it. Do you have to twist my words like that?
정말 진심이었어. 내 말을 꼭 그렇게 비틀어야 합니까?
What you need is my intel, not me.
당신에게 필요한 것은 내가 아닌 내 정보입니다.
That's what makes you indispensable.
그것이 당신을 없어서는 안 될 존재로 만드는 것입니다.
Anyway, pretend not to know me when you see me at the station.
어쨌든 역에서 나를 보면 모른 척 해주세요 .
Goodness. Don't worry.
선량. 괜찮아요.
Life is full of irony.
인생은 아이러니로 가득 차 있습니다.
Song Ha-young and even Yoon Tae-gu.
송하영, 윤태구까지.
Who knew I'd meet them again here?
내가 여기서 다시 만날 줄 누가 알았겠어요?
Is this fate or something?
이게 운명인가 뭔가인가?
Did you meet Inspector Song Ha-young?
송하영 경위를 만나셨나요?
I did.
그랬어요.
I can't figure out what his team does.
그 사람 팀이 무슨 일을 하는지 알 수가 없어요.
When you stab someone in the back, it all comes back--
누군가의 등을 찌르면 모든 것이 되돌아옵니다.
Darn it. There's one exception.
젠장. 한 가지 예외가 있습니다.
Who? You?
WHO? 너?
You little…
이 작은…
The head prosecutor
검찰총장
who asked for Yoon Tae-gu back then.
그때 윤태구를 요구한 사람.
HEAD PROSECUTOR LEE DONG-JU
이동주 부장검사
Here.
여기.
It's classified information, so don't reveal your source.
기밀정보이므로 출처를 밝히지 마세요.
Investigate it alone, quietly.
혼자서 조용히 조사해 보세요.
-This is credible, right? -Have I ever lied to you?
-이거 믿을만한거 맞죠? -내가 당신에게 거짓말을 한 적이 있나요?
Go through it. There's solid evidence too.
그것을 통과하십시오. 확실한 증거도 있어요.
Why did I miss all this?
왜 내가 이 모든 것을 놓쳤는가?
Yoon Tae-gu is one of your direct reports, right?
윤태구씨 가 직속 부하 중 한 명이죠?
Yes, sir.
알겠습니다.
-Hello. -Where is Room 10?
-안녕하세요. - 10호실은 어디에 있나요?
It's this way. You'll find it on your left.
이 방법입니다. 왼쪽에서 찾으실 수 있습니다.
Yoon Tae-gu.
윤태구.
I mean, Detective Yoon.
윤형사님이군요.
We're now getting the hang of working together as a team,
이제 우리는 팀으로 협력하는 방법을 익히고 있습니다 .
and you worked hard on this case, so I want to buy you a drink.
그리고 당신이 이 사건을 위해 열심히 일했기 때문에 나는 당신에게 음료수를 사주고 싶습니다.
Come meet me here.
여기로 오세요.
-I'm telling you. -My goodness.
-내가 말하잖아. -이럴 수가.
There she is. Come on in.
저기 그녀가있다. 들어와.
You made it. Take a seat.
네가 해냈어. 앉아 요.
Come on. Take a seat.
어서 해봐요. 앉아 요.
Come on!
어서 해봐요!
Hey, where are you going?
이봐, 어디 가는 거야?
"Schmoozing"?
"멍때리기"?
-Goodness, the station is a hot mess. -How dare you disgrace the police force?
-맙소사, 역이 엉망이군요. -어떻게 감히 경찰을 모욕할 수 있습니까?
-Detective Yoon, you're something. -Are you satisfied?
-윤형사님, 당신은 대단해요. - 만족하시나요?
The head prosecutor
검사장
who asked for Yoon Tae-gu back then?
그때 누가 윤태구를 요청했나요?
I ended up taking bribes
결국 뇌물을 받았어요
from a building contractor against my will.
내 의지에 반하여 건축업자로부터 .
And arrested a fake suspect.
그리고 가짜 용의자를 체포했습니다.
Due to that, I was branded a corrupt cop.
그 때문에 나는 부패한 경찰이라는 낙인을 찍었습니다.
Everything was set up so he'd look like the real culprit.
그가 진짜 범인처럼 보이도록 모든 것이 준비되었습니다 .
Anyone would've been tricked.
누구라도 속았을 겁니다.
Song Ha-young didn't!
송하영은 그렇지 않았다!
That punk really gets on my nerves.
그 놈이 정말 내 신경을 거슬리게 만드네요.
He has to get in the way of everything I do.
그 사람은 내가 하는 모든 일을 방해해야 해요 .
I got demoted because of him!
그 사람 때문에 내가 강등됐어!
But you're back now.
하지만 이제 돌아왔네요.
Song Ha-young was branded
송하영이 낙인찍혔다
a backstabbing troublemaker who betrays his superiors.
상사를 배신하는 중상모략꾼 .
That's why he's working in that dump of an office now.
그래서 그 사람은 지금 그 쓰레기장에서 일하고 있는 거죠.
That's not enough.
그것은 충분하지 않아.
He acts like a gentleman to your face but skims the cream off the top
그는 당신의 얼굴에 신사처럼 행동 하지만 꼭대기에서 크림을 걷어냅니다.
behind your back.
등 뒤에서.
-Everyone needs to know that. -Bong-sik.
- 모두가 그걸 알아야 해요. -봉식.
I'll only trust Chief Kim Bong-sik, who's back in Seoul now.
이제 서울에 가신 김봉식 과장님만 믿겠습니다 .
Why would you trust me?
왜 나를 믿겠어요?
Don't trust anyone.
누구도 믿지 마십시오.
Goodness, you're hurting my feelings.
맙소사, 당신이 내 감정을 상하게 하고 있어요.
-You don't even trust me? -You little…
-너도 나를 믿지 않는거야? -이 작은…
By the way,
그런데,
the Suseong-dong case in Gangnam.
강남 수성동 사건.
Who is the victim?
피해자는 누구입니까?
Those at Gangnam Police Station are keeping it quiet.
강남경찰서 관계자들은 조용히 지내고 있다.
Hey, today is my first day.
안녕하세요, 오늘이 첫 날이에요.
You must've heard something.
뭔가 들어보셨을 겁니다.
Can I please eat first?
먼저 먹어도 될까요?
Captain Yoon, you're here.
윤대위님, 오셨습니다.
-I heard you asked for me. -What? You came alone?
-나한테 부탁했다고 들었어. -무엇? 혼자 오셨나요?
Bong-sik isn't at his desk?
봉식 씨는 책상에 없어요?
We must be ready to mobilize at all times.
우리는 항상 동원할 준비가 되어 있어야 합니다.
But he can't be reached on his first day?
그런데 첫날에는 연락이 안 된다고요?
Darn it.
젠장.
We need you to take on a case.
당신이 사건을 맡아야 해요.
The victim is Han Seok-hoon a professor at Hankuk University.
피해자는 한석훈 한국대 교수.
He and his wife were murdered in their home two weeks ago.
그와 그의 아내는 2주 전에 집에서 살해당했습니다 .
MURDER OF ELDERLY COUPLE IN SUSEONG-DONG CASE REPORT
수성동 노부부 살해 사건신고
We need you to work on it.
우리는 당신이 그 일을 해야 합니다.
It belongs to Gangnam Station.
강남역에 속해있습니다.
It does fall under their jurisdiction,
그것은 그들의 관할권에 속합니다.
but he's related to someone who is very high up.
하지만 그 사람은 아주 높은 지위에 있는 사람과 관련이 있어요.
I was asked to look into it quietly, so that's all I know.
조용히 알아보라고 해서 제가 아는 건 그것뿐이에요.
But I think they're struggling to find leads.
하지만 내 생각엔 그들이 단서를 찾기 위해 애쓰고 있는 것 같아요.
How do I find a phone number?
전화번호는 어떻게 찾나요?
I think the reporters already caught a whiff of it.
기자들은 이미 그 냄새를 알아차린 것 같아요 .
The higher-ups want us
윗사람들이 우리를 원해
to prevent media coverage and work on it swiftly.
언론보도를 방지 하고 신속하게 조치를 취하겠습니다.
Gangnam Police Station will help you out.
강남경찰서가 도와드리겠습니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
-I'll be off, then. -Okay.
-그럼 난 이만 갈게. -좋아요.
There, I found it.
거기서 찾았어요.
Look at this.
이거 봐요.
This bastard, Kim Bong-sik. He's not picking up.
이 놈, 김봉식. 그는 전화를 받지 않습니다.
Is it an important case?
중요한 사건인가요?
All homicide cases are equally important.
모든 살인 사건은 똑같이 중요합니다.
That's true.
그것은 사실이다.
Why are we working on another station's case?
왜 우리는 다른 방송국의 사건을 조사하고 있나요 ?
We should go there first.
우리 먼저 거기로 가야 해요.
-Chief Kim still isn't at his desk? -No.
- 김과장은 아직도 책상에 안 계시나요? -아니요.
People really don't change.
사람은 정말 안 변해요.
SEPTEMBER 29, 2003
2003년 9월 29일
Are we leaving now? Just the two of us?
이제 떠나는 건가요? 단지 우리의 두?
GUNGOK-DONG, JONGNO SEPTEMBER 24, 2003
종로 군곡동 2003년 9월 24일
REPORTING THE MURDER OF ELDERLY COUPLE IN SUSEONG-DONG AS FOLLOWS
수성동 노부부 살해 사건을 다음과 같이 신고합니다.
Damn it, Im Moo-sik that scumbag…
젠장 임무식 그 쓰레기새끼...
MURDER OF ELDERLY COUPLE IN SUSEONG-DONG CASE REPORT
수성동 노부부 살해 사건신고
The victims of the murder are a couple in their sixties in Suseong-dong.
살인의 피해자는 수성동에 거주하는 60대 부부입니다.
Han Seok-hoon,
한석훈,
a Hankuk University professor, and his wife.
한국대학교 교수 부인
I bet there's something about Han Seok-hoon.
한석훈에 관한 뭔가가 있을 것 같아요 .
Gosh, seriously.
맙소사, 정말요.
I told you not to say the victim's name.
피해자 이름은 말하지 말라고 했어요.
Come on. You need to give me something to write about.
어서 해봐요. 나에게 쓸 내용을 주어야합니다 .
Loyalty isn't a one-way street.
충성은 일방통행이 아닙니다.
They've been preserving the scene for over two weeks now.
그들은 현재 2주 넘게 현장을 보존하고 있습니다 .
There's definitely something.
확실히 뭔가가 있습니다.
You're really telling me nothing?
정말 나한테 아무 말도 안 하는 거야?
Over here.
여기.
Good day. I'm Yoon Tae-gu from Seoul HQ.
안녕하세요. 저는 서울본부 윤태구입니다.
-This is… -Nam Il-young, also from HQ.
-이분은... -역시 본사 남일영입니다.
Yes, I got a call. This way.
응, 전화가 왔어. 이 방법.
-Okay. -Hey, tidy up here.
-좋아요. -야, 여기 좀 정리 좀 해라.
There was cash lying around, but he didn't even touch it.
주변에 현금이 있었지만 그는 손도 대지 않았습니다.
They think it's an act of resentment masked as a burglary.
그들은 그것이 강도를 가장한 원한 행위라고 생각합니다.
It's clean.
깨끗해요.
The victims were overpowered
피해자들은 압도적이었다
without any sort of resistance.
어떤 저항도 없이.
If they had resisted,
그들이 저항했다면,
blood would've splattered to the ceiling as he was swinging his weapon.
무기를 휘두르면 피가 천장에 튀었을 것이다 .
You'll see that the victims' bodies are clean
피해자의 시신이 깨끗한 것을 보게 될 것입니다
with no sign of defense when you get to the morgue later.
나중에 영안실에 도착하면 방어할 기미도 없이 말이죠 .
Gosh, I don't know what this horrifying guy hit them with.
이런, 이 끔찍한 놈이 뭘로 때렸는지 모르겠어요 .
We're trying our best but weren't able to identify it yet.
최선을 다하고 있지만 아직 확인하지 못했습니다.
He came into a rich house like this
그 사람은 이렇게 부잣집에 들어왔어
and only pretended to look for cash.
그리고 현금 찾는 척만 했어요.
It has to be a grudge.
원한이 있어야합니다.
We looked into that, but that seems highly unlikely.
우리는 그것에 대해 조사했지만 그럴 가능성은 거의 없어 보입니다.
Both husband and wife had great reputations.
남편과 아내 모두 좋은 평판을 얻었습니다.
They were high up the social ladder.
그들은 사회적 지위가 높았습니다.
So they may have incurred a grudge from someone without knowing.
그래서 그들은 자신도 모르게 누군가로부터 원한을 품게 되었을 수도 있습니다 .
So it may be the doings of an acquaintance holding a grudge?
그렇다면 원한을 품고 있는 지인의 행동이 아닐까 ?
Should we start around the school?
학교 주변부터 시작할까요?
We already did.
우리는 이미 그랬습니다.
Even if it's an act of resentment,
비록 그것이 원망스러운 행동이라 할지라도,
his method is too bold and violent.
그의 방법은 너무 대담하고 폭력적이다.
Overkilling is common
과잉살인이 흔하다
among murderers targeting acquaintances.
지인을 노리는 살인범들 사이에서.
I doubt that a mentally ill person
정신병자인지 의심스럽네요
would've casually walked into a house like this.
이런 집 에 아무렇지도 않게 들어갔을 거예요 .
Could you give us the list of acquaintances you interviewed?
인터뷰한 지인 목록을 알려주실 수 있나요 ?
Yes, I will.
네, 그럴게요.
Once you get the list, check to see if there's anyone
목록을 받은 후 사람이 있는지 확인하세요.
with a record and mental illness.
기록과 정신 질환이 있습니다.
Yes, ma'am.
네 부인.
Why did a detective from Seoul HQ come to a case in Gangnam?
서울본부 형사가 강남 사건을 맡게 된 이유는 무엇일까?
Yes, sir?
알겠습니다?
Hey! Didn't I tell you to release it first?
여기요! 내가 먼저 풀어놓으라고 하지 않았나요 ?
An article has been released identifying the Suseong-dong victim
수성동 피해자 신원이 밝혀진 기사가 공개됐다.
as Professor Han Seok-hoon!
한석훈교수님!
What?
무엇?
You try to be respectful,
존중하려고 노력합니다.
conscientious, and even loyal.
성실하고, 심지어 충성스럽기까지 합니다.
So when do you plan on getting an exclusive?
그럼 언제 독점권을 얻을 계획인가요 ?
Who wrote that article?
그 기사는 누가 썼나요?
Who do you think? It's Im Moo-sik, of course.
당신은 누구라고 생각합니까? 물론 임무식이다.
Damn! That son of a bitch.
젠장! 그 개자식.
Let's hurry on over.
빨리 끝내자.
SPECIAL CRIME SQUAD, CHIEF KIM BONG-SIK
특수수사대 김봉식 반장
Thank you, Bong-sik.
고마워요 봉식님.
Kook Young-soo.
국영수.
SENIOR INSPECTOR, KOOK YOUNG-SOO
국영수 경감
Gosh, so this is it.
맙소사, 바로 이것이다.
INVESTIGATION RECORD
조사 기록
Having us waste our time by giving us useless things to do.
우리에게 쓸데없는 일을 시켜서 시간을 낭비하게 만듭니다 .
The things these higher-ups come up with from their heads…
윗분들 머리에서 나오는 것들이 ..
What about our heads?
우리 머리는 어떻습니까?
I mean it's always so useful.
내 말은, 그것이 항상 매우 유용하다는 것을 의미한다.
What's with this report? You didn't even try.
이 보고서는 무엇입니까? 당신은 시도조차 하지 않았습니다.
Be more descriptive.
좀 더 자세히 설명하세요.
MURDER OF ELDERLY COUPLE IN SUSEONG-DONG
수성동 노부부 살해 사건
Did you talk to Captain Yoon?
윤 선장이랑 통화했어?
I'm sure she's doing just fine.
나는 그녀가 잘 지내고 있다고 확신합니다.
It's best for superiors to just stand back and do nothing.
상사는 그냥 물러서서 아무것도 하지 않는 것이 가장 좋습니다 .
Are you talking about me?
너 나에 대해 말하는 거니?
Gosh, of course not.
물론 그렇지 않습니다.
Some punk must have leaked the case.
어떤 펑크가 사건을 유출한 게 틀림없어요.
The reporters are already on it.
기자들은 이미 그 일을 하고 있다.
Those damn reporters. They sure are fast.
빌어먹을 기자들아. 확실히 빠릅니다.
Seriously?
진지하게?
They're coming!
그들이 오고 있어요!
Still no leads in Han Seok-hoon's case?
한석훈 사건, 아직 단서가 없어?
Out of resentment?
분노 때문에?
Are you done interviewing?
면접 끝났나요?
-Do you have a suspect? -Were any valuables stolen?
- 용의자가 있나요? -귀중품을 도난 당했습니까?
Is it an acquaintance's doing?
지인이 하는 일인가요?
Answer us, please!
대답해주세요!
HWANG DAE-SUN SECOND INTERVIEW REPORT
황대선 2차 인터뷰 리포트
What was the purpose of carving out the flesh
살을 도려낸 목적은 무엇이었는가
after the victim's death?
피해자가 사망한 후
It looks like you'll have homework tonight.
오늘 밤 숙제가 있을 것 같습니다 .
Still thinking about Hwang Dae-sun?
아직도 황대선을 생각하고 있나요?
You know me.
당신은 나를 알고 있습니다.
Let's start.
시작하자.
Serial murders can be defined by these three things.
연쇄살인은 이 세 가지로 정의할 수 있습니다 .
A psychological cooling-off period.
심리적 냉각 기간.
Crime against a stranger to commit murder.
낯선 사람을 상대로 살인을 저지르는 범죄.
Murdering three or more people, in three or more locations.
3개 이상의 장소에서 3명 이상의 사람을 살해하는 행위 .
Out of all the prisoners we've met,
우리가 만난 죄수들 중에서
Hwang Dae-sun is closest
황대선이 가장 가깝다
to the serial killer category we are researching.
우리가 연구하고 있는 연쇄살인범 카테고리에요 .
He did kill three people,
그는 세 사람을 죽였고,
But he killed them
하지만 그 사람이 그들을 죽였어
in two different cases. He killed one out of impulse.
두 가지 다른 경우에. 그는 충동적으로 한 명을 죽였습니다.
He may have planned the murder,
살인을 계획했을 수도 있고,
but it wasn't part of his initial plan.
그러나 그것은 그의 초기 계획의 일부가 아니었습니다.
I see two were raped and then murdered, and the other was a man.
두 명은 강간을 당하고 살해당했고, 다른 한 명은 남자였습니다.
He had been drinking when committing both cases.
그는 두 사건을 모두 저지를 때 술을 마시고 있었습니다 .
The man was the second victim's boyfriend.
그 남자는 두 번째 피해자의 남자친구였습니다.
Then the boyfriend was murdered out of impulse?
그럼 남자친구는 충동적으로 살해된 건가요?
Exactly.
정확히.
On his way to his girlfriend's house, he witnessed the rape
여자친구 집으로 가던 중 성폭행을 목격했다.
and was murdered.
그리고 살해당했습니다.
All three victims were murdered under the influence.
피해자 3명 모두 술에 취해 살해됐다 .
So it's an unsystematic crime.
그러니까 비조직적인 범죄죠.
Just because he was under the influence
단지 그 사람이 영향을 받았기 때문이다.
doesn't mean that it was an unsystematic crime.
비조직적인 범죄였다는 뜻은 아니다 .
An unsystematic crime
비체계적인 범죄
is when confused behavior is shown during the crime.
범죄 중에 혼란스러운 행동을 보이는 경우입니다 .
In the case of Hwang Dae-sun, we can interpret his acts of
황대순의 경우 그의 행위를 다음과 같이 해석할 수 있다.
binding and carving out the skin as abnormal sexual behaviors.
비정상적인 성적 행동으로 피부를 묶고 조각내는 것 .
So it doesn't add up perfectly.
그래서 완벽하게 합산되지는 않습니다.
If you look at it according to the FBI's categories of crime,
FBI의 범죄 분류 에 따라 살펴보면 ,
a systematic type is someone who has personality issues.
체계적인 유형은 성격 문제가 있는 사람입니다.
An unsystematic type
비체계적인 유형
is someone delusional or schizophrenic.
망상이나 정신 분열증이 있는 사람입니다.
With that in mind, Hwang Dae-sun
이를 염두에 두고 황대선은
isn't someone who has a mental illness
정신병 있는 사람 아닌가
but a systematic type with a personality disorder.
성격장애가 있는 체계적 유형이다 .
This is difficult.
이건 어려워.
In the case of Dae-sun, he showed systematic behavior
대선의 경우 체계적인 행동을 보여주었다.
in how he searched and dealt with victims using tools.
그가 도구를 사용해 피해자를 수색하고 처리한 방식에 대해.
I understand when you tell me.
당신이 나에게 말하면 이해합니다.
But the process of reasoning is always difficult.
하지만 추론의 과정은 늘 어렵다.
All right then.
그럼요.
I think the reason Hwang Dae-sun's case is a serial one
황대선 사건이 연쇄 사건인 것 같아요
is this one. Killing more than three.
이것이다. 3명 이상 살해.
Okay.
좋아요.
But I think it's more accurate to label it as a rape and murder case
근데 내 생각엔 강간살인사건으로 보는 게 더 정확할 것 같아
with continuity.
연속성으로.
Since he had a sexual purpose to it.
그에게는 성적인 목적이 있었기 때문이다.
Right, but there was a bigger chance of him becoming
그렇죠, 하지만 그 사람이 될 가능성이 더 커 졌죠
a serial killer if he hadn't been caught.
잡히지 않았다면 연쇄 살인범이었을 것이다.
I was shocked when I heard he'd killed animals as a kid.
나는 그가 어렸을 때 동물을 죽였다는 말을 듣고 충격을 받았습니다.
It's a classic feature that serial killers have.
연쇄살인범이 갖고 있는 전형적인 특징이다 .
But he didn't have a cooling-off period.
하지만 그에게는 냉각 기간이 없었습니다.
A PSYCHOLOGICAL COOLING-OFF PERIOD
심리적 냉각 기간
The culprit behind the Suseong-dong
수성동 사건의 범인
murder case of the old couple in their sixties
60대 노부부 살인사건
in Gangnam on the 10th has yet to be caught.
10일 강남에서는 아직 적발되지 않았습니다.
People are shocked after the victim was identified
피해자가 확인된 후 사람들은 충격에 빠졌습니다
as Hankuk University's Professor Han Seok-hoon and his wife.
한국대학교 한석훈 교수 부부
Not only did Professor Han teach economics at the university,
한 교수는 대학에서 경제학을 가르쳤을 뿐만 아니라
but he also appeared on TV often to give his economical insights.
그러나 그는 경제적 통찰력을 제공하기 위해 TV에도 자주 출연했습니다 .
His bold attitude led to his popularity.
그의 대담한 태도가 인기를 끌었습니다.
But does there always have to be a cooling-off period?
그런데 항상 냉각 기간이 있어야 합니까 ?
Serial killers feel
연쇄살인범의 기분
the highest form of pleasure in the pure act of killing.
순수한 살인 행위가 주는 최고의 즐거움 .
Once the pleasure ends, they search for a new victim.
즐거움이 끝나면 그들은 새로운 희생자를 찾습니다.
To put it simply, a cooling-off period
쉽게 말하면 쿨링오프 기간이다.
is a period where their sense of satisfaction
만족감을 느끼는 시기이다.
from the murder continues to last.
살인 사건은 계속 지속됩니다.
Once that psychological satisfaction comes to an end,
그 심리적 만족감이 끝나면,
they'll move on to the next murder.
그들은 다음 살인으로 넘어갈 것입니다.
Then what about Hwang Dae-sun?
그렇다면 황대선은 어떨까?
In the case of Hwang Dae-sun,
황대순의 경우
we can't view those periods as a cooling-off period
우리는 그 기간을 냉각 기간으로 볼 수 없습니다
since he was under the influence during all the crimes.
그는 모든 범죄에 영향을 받았기 때문입니다 .
But the fact that they murder again once the period ends
하지만 기간이 끝나면 또 살인을 한다는 사실
is so horrifying.
정말 끔찍해요.
Thankfully, in Korea,
다행히 한국에서는
there haven't been any murder cases
살인 사건은 없었어요
with the purpose of murder and a cooling-off period.
살인을 목적으로 하고 냉각 기간을 두고 있습니다.
It's all just speculation.
그것은 모두 추측일 뿐입니다.
These guys are the reason you said you'd need ten years, right?
당신 이 10년은 필요하다고 말한 이유가 이 사람들이거든요 , 그렇죠?
You said you didn't find
못 찾았다고 하셨어요
any injuries on the back of them, right?
등에는 부상은 없지, 그렇지?
Right, I didn't find any.
그렇죠, 아무것도 못 찾았어요.
It looks clean, right?
깨끗해 보이죠?
Drop me off at the office, please.
저를 사무실에 내려주세요.
You're not going home?
집에 안 갈 거야?
No, I want to organize my thoughts.
아니, 내 생각을 정리하고 싶다.
You can head home first. Good job today.
먼저 집에 가셔도 됩니다. 오늘 수고했어요.
No, I want to stop by Gangnam Police Station.
아니요, 강남경찰서 에 들르고 싶어요 .
I heard it's a mess over there right now.
지금 거기가 엉망이라고 들었어.
SCIENTIFIC INVESTIGATIONS TEAM
과학수사팀
Which team was Gangnam's Professor Han case handed over to?
강남 한교수 사건은 어느 팀에 넘겨졌나?
Special Crime Squad's Team Two.
특수수사대 2팀.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Yes.
예.
Footprints?
발자취?
Yes, all right. I'll get back to you.
응, 알았어. 너에게 다시 돌아갈 게.
It's Jongno Police Station.
종로경찰서입니다.
The Gungok-dong case they sent in last week…
지난주에 그들이 보낸 군곡동 사건 …
They want us to run footprints
그들은 우리가 발자국을 달리기를 원해요
and other evidence via the ex-convict database.
전과자 데이터베이스를 통한 기타 증거 .
-Shall I bring them over? -Yes.
-내가 가져다 드릴까요? -예.
SUSEONG-DONG CASE FOOTPRINTS
수성동 사례발자국
-Here you go. -Thanks.
- 여기요. -감사해요.
What?
무엇?
What is it?
그것은 무엇입니까?
Don't these look similar?
이것들도 비슷해 보이지 않나요?
I think they do.
제 생각에는 그렇습니다.
You finally managed to finish the report.
드디어 보고서를 완성했습니다.
-Congratulations. -Thank you.
-축하해요. -감사합니다.
HWANG DAE-SUN SECOND INTERVIEW REPORT
황대선 2차 인터뷰 리포트
Good job. Let's go now.
잘했어요. 이제 가자.
You can head home.
집으로 가셔도 됩니다.
I'm behind on a lot of work because of this report.
나는 이 보고서 때문에 많은 일을 밀리고 있습니다 .
My gosh, you're unbelievable.
맙소사, 당신은 정말 믿기지 않는군요.
What's the word for this? Workahill?
이것에 대한 단어는 무엇입니까? 워커힐?
-It's "holic." -A workaholic.
- '홀릭'이에요. -일 중독자.
I'll get going.
나는 갈 것이다.
Chu Chu, how about a glass of soju and beer?
츄츄, 소주 한잔 어때요? 맥주 한잔 어때요?
Sounds great!
좋은 것 같아요!
-Good luck. -All right. Bye.
-행운을 빌어요. -괜찮은. 안녕.
-Bye! -Bye.
-안녕! -안녕.
GUNGOK-DONG FAMILY MURDER CASE SEPTEMBER 24, 2003
궁곡동 일가족 살인사건 2003년 9월 24일
UNIDENTIFIED WEAPON
미확인 무기
Both victims do not have
두 피해자 모두
any defense marks or signs of resistance.
방어 표시 또는 저항의 흔적
The culprit beat the victims without giving them a moment…
범인은 피해자들 에게 시간도 주지 않고 구타했는데…
to protect themselves.
자신을 보호하기 위해
GUNGOK-DONG
궁곡동
A type of systematic crime…
조직범죄의 일종…
committed according to a plan.
계획에 따라 약속
The crime is too cruel and daring to conclude
범죄가 너무 잔인하고 결말이 뻔하다
that it was done by an acquaintance.
지인이 한 일입니다.
JINJUNG-DONG, GANGNAM
강남 진지동
The culprit did not take…
범인은...
any money or valuables.
돈이나 귀중품
Who is it?
누구입니까?
DISGUISED AS ROBBERY
강도로 위장한
COMMITTED OUT OF GRUDGE?
원한 때문에 저지른 일인가요?
-Who is it? -Is somebody here?
-누구예요? - 여기 누군가 있나요?
Yes, but I don't hear anything.
예, 하지만 아무 소리도 들리지 않습니다.
It must be a prank.
장난임에 틀림없습니다.
Goodnight.
잘 자요.
That's odd. Okay. Goodnight.
그거 이상 하네. 좋아요. 안녕히 주무세요.
Night.
밤.
PRESUMED AS AN ACQUAINTANCE
지인으로 추정됨
But is there someone who is an ex-convict around Professor Han?
근데 한 교수 주변에 전과자 있는 사람이 있는 걸까요 ?
Is this a way of expressing…
이런 표현방식인가요...
the culprit's emotions caused by a grudge they hold?
범인의 원한으로 인한 감정
GUNGOK-DONG, JONGNO
종로군곡동
DO NOT ENTER, UNDER INVESTIGATION
조사 중이므로 들어가지 마십시오.
15 GUNGOK-DONG
15 궁곡동
SONG YOUNG-CHUL, LEE GEUM-SOON
송영철, 이금순
CASE REPORT
사례 보고서
SEOUL METROPOLITAN POLICE AGENCY
서울지방경찰청
Coming to work now?
지금 출근하시나요?
Yes.
예.
What happened at the crime scene yesterday?
어제 사건 현장에서는 무슨 일이 일어났나요 ?
I thought you weren't interested.
나는 당신이 관심이 없다고 생각했습니다.
Are you actually curious? I'll tell you once we're inside.
실제로 궁금하신가요? 안으로 들어가면 말씀드리겠습니다.
You got a lot bolder, Tae-gu.
많이 대담해졌구나, 태구.
You still have that feisty charm.
아직도 그 늠름한 매력을 갖고 계시네요.
I do not want your evaluation of my charms.
내 매력에 대한 평가를 원하지 않습니다 .
I hope we can just carry out our duties
우리가 임무를 잘 수행할 수 있었으면 좋겠어
without getting in each other's way.
서로 방해하지 않고.
You know how important teamwork is when it comes to violent crimes.
강력범죄에서는 팀워크가 얼마나 중요한지 아시죠 ?
How can you only do your duty?
어떻게 해야 본분만 할 수 있나요?
Tae-gu,
Tae-gu,
do you still have a grudge against me?
아직도 나한테 원한이 있는 거야?
A grudge?
원한?
You're quite delusional.
당신은 꽤 망상적입니다.
I do not have anything against you.
나는 당신에게 반대할 것이 없습니다.
I'm sorry about that.
그 점은 죄송합니다.
But everyone already knows
하지만 이미 다들 알고 있죠
that I'm the bastard.
내가 그 놈이라는 걸.
Right?
오른쪽?
I was also aware of
나도 알고 있었어
how you were a bastard too.
너도 개자식이었잖아.
Isn't that so?
그렇지 않나요?
Let's go inside.
안에 들어 가자.
I should not stop the ace of the Special Crime Squad.
특수수사대 에이스를 막아선 안 된다 .
Shall I, then?
그럼 나도 할까?
Gosh, heartburn.
이런, 속 쓰림.
You still think you can do this job by keeping loyalty
당신은 여전히 ​​충성심을 유지하면 이 일을 할 수 있다고 생각합니다.
even after spending three years here?
여기서 3년을 보냈는데도요?
What should I do with you?
내가 당신을 어떻게 해야 합니까?
You know how strict Detectives Kang and Park are.
강 형사와 박 형사가 얼마나 엄격한지 아시죠 ?
I'm sure Moo-sik
틀림없어 무식아
won't get any information from them anymore.
더 이상 그들로부터 어떤 정보도 얻지 못할 것입니다 .
Detective Park isn't the only detective there.
박형사 만이 그곳에 있는 것은 아니다 .
If anyone leaks intel to Daehan Daily,
누구든지 대한일보에 정보를 유출한다면,
it all turns into Moo-sik's article,
다 무식의 글로 변해버리고
while you're sitting around depending on Detective Park.
당신이 박형사에 의존해서 앉아 있는 동안.
Moo-sik
무식
even steals articles from juniors?
심지어 후배들한테서 물건까지 훔쳐?
Man, talk about lack of conscience.
이봐, 양심의 부족에 대해 이야기해라.
Yes, conscience.
응, 양심.
That won't put food on the table.
그러면 식탁에 음식이 놓이지 않습니다.
I've been running around a lot trying not to starve to death.
굶어죽지 않으려고 여기저기 많이 뛰어다녔어요 .
Sure. You work so hard.
확신하는. 당신은 정말 열심히 일합니다.
You're commendable, aren't you?
당신은 칭찬할 만한 사람이군요, 그렇죠?
My boss is doing a great job at making me slave away.
내 상사는 나를 노예로 만드는 데 큰 역할을 하고 있습니다 .
Forget it.
잊어 버려.
Go out and find an item that is as good a story
나가서 이야기만큼 좋은 아이템을 찾아보세요
as the one you got stolen.
당신이 도난당한 것처럼.
What do you mean? It wasn't ours anyway.
무슨 뜻이에요? 어쨌든 그것은 우리 것이 아니었습니다.
It's Detective Park.
박형사입니다.
Another case at Gangnam Police Station broke out.
강남경찰서에서 또 다른 사건이 터졌다.
-Again? -Yes.
-다시? -예.
Hey, Reporter Choi, keep it up. Run!
안녕하세요, 최 기자님, 힘내세요. 달리다!
Forget all about your conscience and loyalty!
양심과 충성심 은 모두 잊어버리세요 !
Reporter Choi, get us just one good story!
최 기자님, 좋은 이야기 하나만 들려주세요!
Keep up the good work, then.
그럼 계속해서 좋은 일을 하세요.
Man, I like how big this office is.
아, 나는 이 사무실이 얼마나 큰지 좋아한다.
Are you satisfied with your first order on the job?
직장에서의 첫 번째 주문 에 만족하시나요 ?
Captain Kook put a lot of effort into making those.
국선장님이 그걸 만드시 느라 애를 많이 쓰셨어요 .
If it just sits there,
그냥 거기 앉아 있으면
think how awkward he'll feel.
그 사람이 얼마나 기분이 나쁠지 생각해 보세요.
So what will they do with all that information?
그렇다면 그들은 그 모든 정보로 무엇을 하게 될까요?
No idea.
몰라.
He'll use it as his pillow or something.
그는 그것을 베개로 사용할 것입니다.
I'm sure Captain Kook
분명 국 선장님이겠지
will make good use of everything.
모든 것을 잘 활용하겠습니다.
Make sure you check and take everything as needed!
꼭 확인 하고 필요에 따라 모든 것을 가져가세요!
-Yes, sir.
-알겠습니다.
-In-tak. -Hey, Young-soo.
-인탁. -안녕하세요, 영수 씨.
Is something going on?
무슨 일이 일어나고 있나요?
Gangnam Station needed backup. We're heading to Jinjung-dong.
강남역은 백업이 필요했습니다. 진지동으로 향하고 있습니다.
What about you?
당신은 어때요?
I have to check some footprints.
발자국을 좀 확인해야 해요.
I see. Keep it up.
알겠어요. 계속하세요.
-Okay. -Wait.
-좋아요. -기다리다.
To your office, right?
네 사무실로 가는 거 맞지?
-I'm fine. Get back to work. -I'll go with you.
-잘 지내요. 다시 일하세요. - 나도 같이 갈게.
Hey, I'm still going strong.
이봐, 난 아직 강해지고 있어.
Just get back to work.
그냥 일하러 돌아가세요.
-Seriously? -Bye.
-진지하게? -안녕.
-Are you sure? -Yes.
-확실합니까? -예.
If you get stuck, feel free to bring it to us.
막히면 언제든지 우리에게 가져오세요.
-Bye. -Be careful!
-안녕. -조심하세요!
-Yes, there. -Newsflash.
-네, 거기 있어요. -뉴스속보.
This afternoon in Jinjung-dong, Gangnam,
오늘 오후, 강남 진지동
a woman in her fifties was found dead after being struck by a blunt weapon.
50대 여성이 둔기에 맞아 숨진 채 발견됐다.
The police were dispatched for an investigation
수사를 위해 경찰이 파견되었습니다
after a report made by Lee, the maid,
하녀 이씨의 보고 이후
who saw the collapsed victim in her home.
집에서 쓰러진 피해자를 본 사람.
Gangnam Police Station said the culprit of today's
강남경찰서는 오늘의 범인을 밝혔다
Jinjung-dong and the Suseong-dong incident are…
진중동 과 수성동 사건은…
Chief Heo, what on earth is going on?
허과장님 도대체 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 걸까요?
I told you to investigate this quietly. Why is it blowing up?
조용히 조사하라고 했어요. 왜 터지는 걸까요?
Captain Yoon and Detective Nam are at the scene right now.
현재 윤 대위와 남 형사가 현장에 있다.
-Let's hear from them once they return. -Good grief.
-돌아오면 그들의 소식을 들어보자. -맙소사.
Where's Kim Bong-sik?
김봉식 씨는 어디 있어요?
No idea. But he'll crawl back
몰라. 하지만 그 사람은 다시 기어오를 거야
if he thinks this will affect his performance.
이것이 그의 성과에 영향을 미칠 것이라고 그가 생각한다면 .
That's his deal.
그게 그의 거래야.
Look at how big this case has become.
이번 사건이 얼마나 커졌는지 보세요.
We might end up taking over
우리가 결국 인수하게 될지도 몰라
both of these cases.
이 두 경우 모두.
Tell me about it.
그것에 대해 말해주십시오.
These reporters already began to say that they're related or something.
이 기자들은 이미 서로 관련이 있다거나 뭐라 말하기 시작했습니다 .
I have a bad feeling about this.
나는 이것에 대해 나쁜 느낌을 가지고 있습니다.
We can't let this happen.
우리는 이런 일이 일어나도록 놔둘 수 없습니다.
Okay. Who is it?
좋아요. 누구입니까?
Excuse me.
실례합니다.
Hey.
여기요.
-Hello.
-안녕하세요.
What brings you here?
여기에서 당신을 제공합니다?
I found something weird.
뭔가 이상한 걸 발견했어요.
-I wanted your opinion on this. -What is it?
- 이에 대한 귀하의 의견을 듣고 싶습니다. -이게 뭐죠?
-Both are hiking shoes. -Yes.
- 둘 다 등산화입니다. -예.
What about them?
그들은 어떻습니까?
This one is from Suseong-dong, Gangnam.
강남 수성동에서 온 제품입니다.
And this one is from Gungok-dong, Jongno.
그리고 이건 종로 군곡동에서 나온 거예요.
They match, right?
일치하지 않나요?
They're from different areas but the same culprit?
지역은 다르지만 범인은 같다?
A LUXURIOUS RESIDENTIAL HOUSE IN GUNGOK-DONG
궁곡동의 고급 주거용 주택
My mom cooked breakfast for me. I ate it and went to work.
엄마는 나를 위해 아침을 요리해 주셨다. 그거 먹고 출근했어요.
When I called, she didn't answer.
내가 전화했을 때, 그녀는 대답하지 않았습니다.
So I came home and…
그래서 집에 왔는데...
Did anyone hold grudges against her?
그녀에게 원한을 품은 사람이 있었나요?
Or did she have any money problems?
아니면 돈 문제가 있었나요?
None.
없음.
Did she ever sound upset on the phone?
그녀가 전화로 화난 소리를 한 적이 있나요?
No.
아니요.
Hey.
여기요.
What? There was another case in Jinjung-dong.
무엇? 진주동에서는 또 다른 사건이 있었습니다.
-What? -Look at this.
-무엇? -이거 봐요.
I'm reading it now.
지금 읽고 있어요.
"A woman living in her fifties in Jinjung-dong was found dead
" 진중동 50대 여성, 숨진 채 발견됐다"
from blunt force trauma."
둔기에 의한 외상 때문입니다."
UNIDENTIFIED BLUNT WEAPON
미확인 둔기
-So was the victim in Gungok-dong. -Right?
-군곡동 피해자도 마찬가지였다. -오른쪽?
I'll check out the scene.
현장을 확인해보겠습니다.
I'm going to the Special Crime Squad.
특수범죄수사대로 가겠습니다.
As the media says, this case has similarities
언론에서 말하는 대로 이 사건은 유사점이 있다
to Professor Han's case.
한 교수의 경우다.
What? Then it wasn't a revenge killing?
무엇? 그럼 보복살인이 아니었나요?
We'll have to investigate more,
좀 더 조사해봐야겠습니다,
but we don't have any suspects in Professor Han's case.
하지만 한 교수 사건에는 어떤 용의자도 없습니다 .
They both died
둘 다 죽었어
from blunt force trauma to the head.
둔기 외상에서 머리까지.
And it was staged as a robbery?
그리고 그것은 강도로 꾸며졌습니까?
Yes.
예.
Gil-pyo. Chief.
길표. 셰프.
Hey, we're busy. Come back later.
안녕하세요, 우리는 바빠요. 나중에 다시 오세요.
-Check this out now. -Come back later.
- 지금 확인해 보세요. -나중에 다시 오세요.
Just look at this.
이것 좀 보세요.
Hiking shoes.
하이킹 신발.
What about them?
그들은 어떻습니까?
In-tak brought them to me.
인탁이가 가져다 줬어요.
The first is from Suseong-dong. The second is from Gungok-dong.
첫 번째는 수성동 출신이다. 두 번째는 군곡동 출신이다.
Suseong-dong is in Gangnam. Gungok-dong is in Jongno.
수성동은 강남에 있어요. 군곡동은 종로에 있어요.
-Give me that. -It's the same guy.
- 그거 주세요. -같은 사람이에요.
I read the reports. It's the same MO.
나는 보고서를 읽었습니다. 같은 MO입니다.
-Blunt force trauma? -Yes. Exactly.
-둔기에 의한 외상? -예. 정확히.
Suseong-dong and Gungok-dong. They were hit in the head.
수성동과 군곡동. 그들은 머리를 맞았습니다.
The victim in Jinjung-dong also died from--
진정동 피해자 역시 다음과 같은 이유로 사망했다.
You knew?
알고 있었나요?
I just got back
난 그냥 돌아왔다
from the crime scene in Jinjung-dong.
진지동 범죄현장에서요.
Who on earth is this guy?
도대체 이 사람은 누구일까요?
The MO is the same.
MO도 똑같습니다.
Why are you here?
당신은 왜 여기에 있습니까?
Let me in.
나를 들여 보내줘.
You're not an investigator. Why?
당신은 조사관이 아닙니다. 왜?
-I need to see the crime scene. -Leave!
-범죄 현장을 봐야 해요. -떠나다!
Don't try to steal my case. Get lost!
내 케이스를 훔치려고 하지 마세요. 길을 잃다!
Please. I must check the crime scene.
제발. 범죄 현장을 확인해야 해요.
Hey. Didn't you hear me?
여기요. 내 말 못 들었어?
I told you to get lost, you bastard!
내가 길을 잃으라고 했잖아, 이 새끼야!
Damn it.
젠장.
This is important.
이건 중요하다.
The victim was hit by a blunt weapon.
피해자가 둔기에 맞았습니다.
UNIDENTIFIED BLUNT WEAPON
미확인 둔기
There are no footsteps in the bedroom.
침실에는 발자국 소리가 없습니다.
And the safe wasn't touched either.
그리고 금고도 건드리지 않았습니다.
CRIME SCENE STEPPING PLATES
범죄 현장 디딤판
There's no trace of blood splattered on the ceiling.
천장에 혈흔이 튀지 않았습니다 .
It means…
그 의미는...
the culprit subdued the victim with one blow.
범인은 일격으로 피해자를 제압했습니다 .
-Yes. -Are you there?
-예. -거기 계세요?
What do we do?
우리는 무엇을해야합니까?
I thought we had ten years.
나는 우리에게 10년이 있다고 생각했다.
But it happened too quickly.
그러나 그것은 너무 빨리 일어났다.
This killer checks all the boxes.
이 살인자는 모든 상자를 확인합니다.
1. A PSYCHOLOGICAL COOLING-OFF PERIOD
1. 심리적 냉각 기간
2. CRIME AGAINST A STRANGER TO COMMIT MURDER
2. 낯선 사람에 대한 살인 범죄
3. MURDERING THREE OR MORE PEOPLE IN THREE OR MORE LOCATIONS
3. 세 곳 이상의 장소에서 세 명 이상의 사람을 살해하는 행위
The police admitted the recent killings in wealthy neighborhoods
경찰은 최근 부유한 동네에서 발생한 살인 사건을 인정했습니다
could have been part of a serial killing.
연쇄살인의 일부였을 수도 있습니다.
The police will consider the three murder cases
경찰은 세 건의 살인 사건을 검토할 예정이다
in Gangnam and Jongno as serial murder cases
강남, 종로 연쇄살인사건
and do their best to find the culprit
범인을 찾기 위해 최선을 다합니다
by dispatching more resources to these areas.
이러한 지역에 더 많은 자원을 파견합니다 .
There have been murder cases in Suseong-dong and Jinjung-dong,
수성동과 진지동에서 살인사건이 발생했고 ,
back to back.
연속해서.
And between these two cases, a similar murder case
그리고 이 두 사건 사이에는 비슷한 살인 사건
took place in Gungok-dong, Jongno-gu.
종로구 군곡동에서 진행되었습니다.
And the late discovery of the news has put the residents in fear.
그리고 이 소식이 뒤늦게 밝혀지면서 주민들은 두려움에 빠졌습니다.
DO NOT ENTER, UNDER INVESTIGATION
조사 중이므로 들어가지 마십시오.
The culprit went to different areas,
범인은 다른 지역으로 갔습니다.
and his only purpose was to kill.
그리고 그의 유일한 목적은 살인이었습니다.
This is the third murder.
이번이 세 번째 살인입니다.
Please do not cross.
건너지 마십시오.
What happened here?
여기 뭔 일 있었 니?
It's a serial murder.
연쇄살인입니다.
A woman in her sixties was found dead in a residential area in Hwanghwa-dong.
황화동 주택가에서 60대 여성이 숨진 채 발견됐다 .
The police launched an investigation.
경찰이 수사에 착수했습니다.
-A blunt weapon was used. -The triangle again?
-둔기가 사용되었습니다. - 또 삼각형이요?
Something is off. I'm sure he came across an unexpected situation.
문제가 발생했습니다. 나는 그가 예상치 못한 상황에 직면했다고 확신합니다 .
You guys in the Analysis Team should return to the office.
분석팀 여러분은 사무실로 돌아가세요.
Entering the crime scene as they please is obstructing the investigation.
범죄 현장에 마음대로 들어가는 것은 수사를 방해하는 것입니다.
The answers are always found at the scene.
답은 언제나 현장에서 찾을 수 있습니다.
-What are we supposed to do with that? -We can buy time.
- 그걸로 우리는 무엇을 해야 합니까? -시간을 살 수 있어요.
Don't tell me you're buying this nonsense.
이런 말도 안되는 소리를 하고 있다고 말하지 마세요.
The only way to prevent him from committing the next murder…
그가 다음 살인을 저지르는 것을 막을 수 있는 유일한 방법은 …
is this.
이것이다.